<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A techie blog!</title>
    <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A techie blog!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:49:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Key to success: Consistency</title>
      <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2022-01-06-key_to_success_consistency/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:49:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2022-01-06-key_to_success_consistency/</guid>
      <description>Intro I am going to write a few blog posts on things I consider are most important for success. This is part 1 of this series.
Everyone needs to define meaning of success, what it means. A poor guy might want money, ill person would want health, an old would desire to have their youth once more. Everyone has their own definition. So it is important to define one&amp;rsquo;s own definition of success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is success</title>
      <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2022-01-06-what_is_success/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 12:49:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2022-01-06-what_is_success/</guid>
      <description>Intro Success is a relative topic. One needs to grasp this concept to be happy. Success is about being the best in a class/field, but success is also to be able to spend time with family after a rough day and still smile and be with them. Success is also being able to play with your mom/dad after coming back from school. Success is health during these tough times, its being able to get medical care and vaccine and its also having others around you be aware of the importance of being vaccinated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dotfiles: Why you need them and how to use them.</title>
      <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2021-10-21-dotfiles_why_you_need_them_and_how_to_use_them/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 19:39:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2021-10-21-dotfiles_why_you_need_them_and_how_to_use_them/</guid>
      <description>Every pragmatic programmer has their own preference when it comes to tools, IDE, etc. Nowadays even desktop setup, keyboards etc.
I am going to highlight one such preference of tools and setups.
It&amp;rsquo;s a great idea to keep a list of popular software you need and any packages for text editors or IDE.
Let&amp;rsquo;s focus on macos which I am using since last 4 years now. Doing a similar setup in linux is straight forward and could be done in windows too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notetaking for the long run</title>
      <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2021-09-09-notetaking_for_the_long_run/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 14:59:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2021-09-09-notetaking_for_the_long_run/</guid>
      <description>In tech world, one would want a second brain. Yes right! if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of second brain it is just a personal data storage where one could query for data. This second brain helps you focus on things that are important to you and to your work.
There is the Zettelkasten method of notetaking which I find very helpful. I am not trying to reinvent the wheel, but just laying out the ideas which I think are most helpful during and after notetaking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus tut - Monitoring and Alarms</title>
      <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2021-09-08-prometheus_tut_monitor_and_alarms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 11:22:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2021-09-08-prometheus_tut_monitor_and_alarms/</guid>
      <description>Why is monitoring an important part of micro services architecture? Softwares need to be reliable and available most of the times. This has revolutionized the way softwares are created. Thus monitoring services is a critical piece which allows us to control systems. The more complex a system gets, harder it is to understand its performance and troubleshoot problems.
Prometheus Prometheus is an open source software for monitoring systems. It stores its metrics as a time series data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decorator (waffle) design pattern</title>
      <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2021-01-31-decorator_waffle_design_pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 22:20:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2021-01-31-decorator_waffle_design_pattern/</guid>
      <description>Design pattern that&amp;rsquo;s like a waffle For ones who love waffles get to choose from a wide variety - StrawberryWaffle, BlackberryWaffle, BananaWaffle, WalnutWaffle.
For a chef this is not a complex recipe. They make plain waffles and then put toppings based on customer choice.
What&amp;rsquo;s a waffle got to do with Design pattern? Well, let&amp;rsquo;s say if you are trying to print a receipt it would have a header, item details and a footer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 12:09:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>          Send me a message on linkedin. Follow me on github. Found a mistake in blog? Send me an email    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running plan during pandemic, 2020</title>
      <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2021-01-14-running-lifestyle-during-pandemic-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 09:40:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2021-01-14-running-lifestyle-during-pandemic-2020/</guid>
      <description>Running Running has been a part of my life since my bachelor&amp;rsquo;s and I have found one way or other to keep at it. During the 2020 lockdown it was difficult to run outside and I didn&amp;rsquo;t like running with my mask on. I thought of buying a treadmill to keep myself active.
So far I have made a schedule and have stuck with it for sometime now. I thought it would be a good thing to share with everyone who might find it informational / motivational.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programmers best friend IDE</title>
      <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2020-09-12-programmers-best-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2020-09-12-programmers-best-friend/</guid>
      <description>A programmer needs a good IDE A good IDE is a programmers best friend. Writing clean code requires one to spend time in their code base and to have a look and feel of various parts of code. Search files, syntax highlighting, completions, renaming, formatting with fmt flavored styles etc are few of the many things that programmers rely on to write clean code.
Its of paramount importance that one knows their own IDE same as they would know about the car they drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is this another blog?</title>
      <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2020-07-21-is-this-another-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2020-07-21-is-this-another-blog/</guid>
      <description>object Hello { println(&amp;#34;Hello World!&amp;#34;) } Having written a lot of hello world programs I want to share my experience with other developers. I could use feedback from peers.
I am going to document code snippets, concepts, tech news, interview tips, lifestyle, and a few random stuff.
I will provide a platform to request topics, and or share ideas with me in future. But let&amp;rsquo;s start with baby steps.
So, Hey!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to remove null from code?</title>
      <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2020-07-21-the-one-with-null/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/posts/2020-07-21-the-one-with-null/</guid>
      <description>Introduction  Scala: Though the concepts mentioned in this post are related to Scala, they are universal.
 Thought: A program should not use null.
Null, if not handled, can be troublesome just like an unhandled exception. One should actively try and avoid its usage.
Here are a couple of ways to avoid them.
How to avoid them? Without initial default value  What to do when a var field in a class or method doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an initial default value?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/content/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/content/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently working as a Lead Software Developer at BXBDigital, a Brambles company. I have keen interest in core computer science concepts like Compiler Design, Data Structures, Algorithms, Data Mining, Distributed Computing and Machine Learning.
I have completed my masters in Computer Sciences from University of Delaware. During the course of my masters I was a part-time mobile application developer and later a research assistant under Dr Pollock Lori on a cloud based NSF(National Science Foundation) funded project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/content/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/content/about/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently working as a Lead Software Developer at BXBDigital, a Brambles company. I have keen interest in core computer science concepts like Compiler Design, Data Structures, Algorithms, Data Mining, Distributed Computing and Machine Learning.
I have completed my masters in Computer Sciences from University of Delaware. During the course of my masters I was a part-time mobile application developer and later a research assistant under Dr Pollock Lori on a cloud based NSF(National Science Foundation) funded project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/content/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/content/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently working as a Lead Software Developer at BXBDigital, a Brambles company. I have keen interest in core computer science concepts like Compiler Design, Data Structures, Algorithms, Data Mining, Distributed Computing and Machine Learning.
I have completed my masters in Computer Sciences from University of Delaware. During the course of my masters I was a part-time mobile application developer and later a research assistant under Dr Pollock Lori on a cloud based NSF(National Science Foundation) funded project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhijeetsrivastava.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently working as a Lead Software Developer at BXBDigital, a Brambles company. I have keen interest in core computer science concepts like Compiler Design, Data Structures, Algorithms, Data Mining, Distributed Computing and Machine Learning.
I have completed my masters in Computer Sciences from University of Delaware. During the course of my masters I was a part-time mobile application developer and later a research assistant under Dr Pollock Lori on a cloud based NSF(National Science Foundation) funded project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
